

neel747hp@gmail.com



Portfolio



Gandhinagar, Gujarat

EDUCATION

Gujarat Techological University (GTU)

Bachelor's Degree: 2018-2022

Information Technology (I.T.)

CGPA: 9.22

S.E.M. High School

High School: 2016-2018

Study Field: Science (PCM)

CGPA: 6.52

CERTIFICATIONS

Azure Fundamentals (Microsoft)

Azure Data Fundamentals (Microsoft)

Deep Learning (IIT Madras - NPTEL)

Data Analytics (AWS)

Machine Learning (Stanford - Coursera)

Excel - Data Analytics (Linkedin)

HONORS & AWARDS

1st Rank in 1st, 4th & 5th Sem in Academics (College Level)

BigShot Hackathon Winner (Inter College Level

Kho-Kho Champions (Zone Level)

Neel Patel

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

PROFILE

With nearly two years of experience in the I.T. sector, I am a Computer Engineer who specializes in data engineering, web application optimization, and debugging. My primary motivation stems from the outcomes yielded by data analysis, and I am consistently driven to achieve precision, accuracy, and personal satisfaction. I firmly believe in the value of lifelong learning and continuously seek out opportunities to expand my knowledge and skillset.

EXPERIENCE

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICE (TCS)

Jun 2022 - Present

Full-Stack Developer

I created web applications and APIs that were capable of processing, analyzing, and visually displaying data.

My responsibility was on optimizing the efficiency, data quality, and flexibility of these applications.

I was responsible for the entire development process, including planning, writing, and debugging, ensuring complete accuracy.

PERSISTENT SYSTEMS

Feb 2022 - Jun 2022

SDE Intern

Optimize the data retrieving applied Ajax calls in Web Applications and decrease data retrieving time by up to 60%.

- Got hands-on exposure to SQL, Core Java, Spring Boot, Javascript, and Bootstrap.
- · Done data transformation and preprocessing to be analysisready.

SKILLS

OS

: Python, J2EE (JAVA 8), SQL, JS, Languages

: Linux, Windows

jQuery, DSA, XML, HTML, CSS, JDBC

Libraries / Frameworks: Spring Boot, Hibernate, Numpy, Pandas : GCP, Azure, Jupyter, GIT, SVN, Octave

Tools / Platforms Database : MySQL, MongoDB

Area of Interest : Data Analytics, ML, Data Admin

HOBBIES

Football

Swimming

Cricket

Anchoring

PROJECTS

Color Detection from Image | Link

Open CV, Python, Data Preprocessing

The Computer Vision field frequently employs Color Detection. My model, for instance, can identify a chosen color from an image and provide its corresponding RGB values and name. The model predicts the color based on the selected pixel.

Face Mask Detection (Near Real Time) | Link

Open CV, Python, Keras, MobileNet, Data Processing

Based on real-time video frames we are detecting the Mask on the Human Face.

Here we are using two models, 2000 approx pre-processed lmage data will fit into the pre-trained MobileNet V2 model & from its output, we will create our classification model for prediction.

Using the FaceNet model to detect the face in real-time frames and send it to our model for prediction & deliver output in no time.

Parkinson's Disease Prediction I Link

PCA, SVC, Python

The main objective of this project is to detect the early onset of Parkinson's disease.

By using Principle component Analysis (PCA) I detected the core symptoms that show maximum impact, and I used different

models like KNN Algorithm, Support Vector Classifier (SVC) and Random Forest Algorithm.

Garbage Segmentation System

Firebase, HTML, CSS

We designed an application that scans the Quick Response Code of dustbins. After it detects keep the records that garbage is being collected from everywhere.

This will update the database records that all targeted area waste has been collected successfully 90-95% every day.